# JOSEPH FAULSTICK

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER 6175382734

## • DETAILS •

6175382734 jfaulstick@gmail.com

LINKS

https://github.com/jfaulstick

• SKILLS •

HTML

CSS

JavaScript

TypeScript

ReactJS

**AngularJS** 

Angular 6+

Karma

Jest

Node.js

MySQL

MongoDB

**REST APIs** 

Git

Agile Development

**Project Management** 

# PROFILE

**Bio:** I am a Software Developer with experience working with modern frameworks. In addition, I have a 15 year background in the video game industry with 14 years served in a Producer role with a proven track record for producing quality, award-winning AAA titles such as BioShock and Civilization VI.

**Skills:** HTML, CSS,, JavaScript, jQuery, Node, AngularJS/6+, React, MySQL, MongoDB, Firebase, Git.

Contact: jfaulstick@gmail.com

#### EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

## Junior Front End Engineer at FoodLogiQ, Durham

February 2019 — Present

Currently serving as a junior front end engineer supporting FoodLogiQ's Connect platform.

Responsibilities include:

- Implement new front end product features to FoodLogiQ's core Connect platform.
- Write and maintain unit tests for all front end features using Karma and Jest.
- Assist in upgrading five year old code base from AngularJS 1.3 to a hybrid Angular 8 /
  AngularJS application with the longterm goal of transitioning fully to modern angular.

# Front End Engineer at Smashing Boxes, Durham, North Carolina

August 2018 — February 2019

Served as a member of an embedded team working with one of Smashing Boxes' largest clients. Responsibilities include:

- Plan and develop new features using Angular 6 & 7, TypeScript, and client's internal UI kit.
- Participate in code review and maintenance using Git and Phabricator.
- Assist in the hiring process for the front end engineering team.

# Teaching Assistant at University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, Raleigh-Durham, North Carolina Area

June 2018 — May 2019

Help facilitate classroom operation including, time tracking, attendance, and lesson material delivery.

- Assist in delivering the lesson plan and curriculum.
- Provide mentor-ship and code review to enrolled students during class activities and office hours.
- · Assist students in debugging code through pair programming.

# Producer at 2K, Novato, California

April 2015 — April 2018

Served as development producer on an unannounced title.

- Built initial project, high level milestone schedule, and staffing plans.
- Helped drive forward internal concept and pre-production work using agile methodologies.

Served as the publishing producer for the *Sid Meier's Civilization* franchise while shipping *Sid Meier's Civilization VI*, *Civilization Beyond Earth: Rising Tide*, and *Civilization Revolution 2 Vita*.

Managed milestone review, age rating certification, localization, and quality assurance testing processes.

Mentored and managed junior production staff.

#### Producer at Crystal Dynamics, Redwood City, California

September 2014 — April 2015

Served as a development producer on Rise of the Tomb Raider

- Managed the combat, enemy character, secondary systems, and user interface teams.
- Maintained project schedule for the above areas of development.
- · Ran daily stand-ups and weekly pod meetings.

#### Producer at Microsoft, Redmond, Washington

May 2012 — July 2014

Served as publishing producer on Ryse: Son of Rome, Sunset Overdrive, and Quantum Break.

- · Reviewed development milestones and interim builds.
- Managed final release processes for main title and post release game updates.
- Configured title Live Services via the Xbox Development Portal.
- Ensured titles adhered to internal privacy and security policies.

#### Producer at Freelance, Revere, Massachusetts

May 2011 — May 2012

Provided freelance production consult services for Irrational Games with PR and Marketing efforts for *BioShock Infinite*, including Pre-E3 and E3 2011, Gamescom 2011, Destination Playstation 2011, and additional smaller press and retailer events.

#### Producer at Irrational Games, Quincy, Massachusetts

February 2004 — May 2011

Served as a development producer on Swat 4, BioShock, and BioShock Infinite.

- Managed production and scheduling for significant portions of each title through all phases of development.
- Produced and demonstrated multiple award winning consumer and press demos.
- Managed internal QA test team and mentored junior production staff.
- Assisted in the recruiting process while growing the studio staff from around 45 members to a team of over 100.

# Quality Assurance Tester at Atari, Beverly, Massachusetts

February 2003 — February 2004

Served as a Quality Assurance Tester at Atari's Beverly, Massachusetts studio prior to the studio's closure. Credited on *Unreal Tournament 2004*, *Neverwinter Nights: Hordes of the Underdark*, *Neverwinter Nights: Shadows of Angmar*, *Pajama Sam: Life is Rough When You Lose Your Stuff*, *Rollercoaster Tycoon 2: Wacky Worlds Expansion*.

# EDUCATION

Full Stack Development Certificate, University of California, Berkeley, Berkeley, California October 2017 — April 2018

Attended USC Berkeley's Coding Bootcamp and received an 3.8 grade average on all assignments and class projects.